{"today":"Tue Dec 17 2024","questions":[{"QuestionID":"GIRAlpha00001","Question":"Select the related letter/word/number from the given alternatives.<br/>ACEG : SUWY :: BDFH : ?","Options":{"1":"TVZX","2":"RTZV","3":"TVXZ","4":"RTVZ"},"Answer":"TVXZ"},{"QuestionID":"GIRWdFmt00001","Question":"Select the related letter/word/number from the given alternatives.<br/>Sty : Pig :: Byre : ?","Options":{"1":"Eagle","2":"Cow","3":"Tiger","4":"Hen"},"Answer":"Cow"},{"QuestionID":"GKHistIn00003","Question":"Which was the forst matal used by man ?","Options":{"1":"Copper","2":"Silver","3":"Bronze","4":"Brass"},"Answer":"Copper"},{"QuestionID":"GKGiogra00009","Question":"The Saturn rings were discovered by","Options":{"1":"Copernicus","2":"Newton","3":"Galileo","4":"None of these"},"Answer":"Galileo"},{"QuestionID":"GKGiogra00013","Question":"japan is called 'land of the rising sun' because","Options":{"1":"Sun rises there as soon as it sets","2":"Sun always remains in the eastern part of the sky throughout the day in Japan","3":"Japan being the Eastern-most country in the World, it has the earliest sunrise","4":"The rays of the sun get reflected from the water of the sea and make the sunrise beautiful in Japan"},"Answer":"Japan being the Eastern-most country in the World, it has the earliest sunrise"},{"QuestionID":"GKIndPol00004","Question":"National Human Right Commission was established on","Options":{"1":"October 12, 1993","2":"October 10, 1993","3":"December 10, 1992","4":"january 27, 1991"},"Answer":"October 12, 1993"},{"QuestionID":"GKIndPol00008","Question":"Which artical separates Jammu & Kashmir from rest of the India","Options":{"1":"Article 370","2":"Article 360","3":"Article 268","4":"Article 361"},"Answer":"Article 370"},{"QuestionID":"GKIndEco00014","Question":"The contribution of agriculture to India's Economy is","Options":{"1":"Increasing","2":"Decreasing","3":"Constent","4":"None of the above"},"Answer":"Decreasing"},{"QuestionID":"GKIndEco00010","Question":"What is Laissez-faire?","Options":{"1":"Mixed economy","2":"Controlled economy","3":"Non-Interference of Government in economic affairs","4":"None of the above"},"Answer":"Non-Interference of Government in economic affairs"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenSci00008","Question":"Old—written material, which cannot be read easily, can be read by","Options":{"1":"Cosmic rays","2":"Ultraviolet rays","3":"Infrared rays","4":"None of these"},"Answer":"Infrared rays"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenSci00004","Question":"Which of the following is used as a coolant in nuclear reactors ?","Options":{"1":"Heavy water","2":"Cadmium","3":"Liquid sodium","4":"Graphite"},"Answer":"Liquid sodium"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenSci00006","Question":"Optic fibres are mainly used for which of the following ?","Options":{"1":"Communication","2":"Weaving","3":"Musical instruments","4":"Food industry"},"Answer":"Communication"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenSci00010","Question":"The best colour(s) for a sun umbrella will be ","Options":{"1":"Black","2":"Black on top and white on the inside","3":"White on top and black on the inside","4":"Printed with all the seven colours of rainbow"},"Answer":"White on top and black on the inside"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenKnw00009","Question":"Ogaden region has been a source of conflict between which countries ?","Options":{"1":"Morocco and Algeria","2":"Nigeria and Cameroon","3":"Angola and Zambia","4":"Ethiopia and Somalia"},"Answer":"Ethiopia and Somalia"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenKnw00006","Question":"Which of these international tennis events is played on a grass court ?","Options":{"1":"US Open","2":"French Open","3":"Wimbledon","4":"Australian Open"},"Answer":"Wimbledon"},{"QuestionID":"GKGenKnw00010","Question":"The oldest Monary in the world that of ","Options":{"1":"Nepal","2":"Saudi Arabia","3":"Japan","4":"UK"},"Answer":"Japan"},{"QuestionID":"GKCorSci00004","Question":"The temperature of Oxy-acetylene flame is around","Options":{"1":"2800℃","2":"3200℃","3":"4000℃","4":"1500℃"},"Answer":"3200℃"},{"QuestionID":"GKCorSci00005","Question":"Hard steel contains","Options":{"1":"2 to 5 % carbon","2":"0.5 to 1.5 % carbon","3":"0.1 to 0.4 % carbon","4":"0.01 to 0.04 % carbon"},"Answer":"0.5 to 1.5 % carbon"},{"QuestionID":"GKCurAff00001","Question":"WIKILEAKS, a whistleblower website is an international organization based in?","Options":{"1":"U.S.A","2":"U.K","3":"Sweden","4":"Norway"},"Answer":"Sweden"},{"QuestionID":"GKCurAff00004","Question":"As per the 2011 population census, the most populous state in the country is","Options":{"1":"Madhya Pradesh","2":"Utter Pradesh","3":"West Bengal","4":"Rajasthan"},"Answer":"Utter Pradesh"},{"QuestionID":"GKCurAff00002","Question":"The latest official language of U.N is","Options":{"1":"Russian","2":"Arabic","3":"Chinese","4":"Spanish"},"Answer":"Arabic"},{"QuestionID":"GKCurAff00003","Question":"Through which state does the river Chambal flows ?","Options":{"1":"M.P., Gujarat, U.P","2":"Rajasthan, M.P., Bihar","3":"Gujarat, M.P., Chhattisgarh","4":"U.P., M.P., Rajasthan"},"Answer":"U.P., M.P., Rajasthan"},{"QuestionID":"GKBokAut00001","Question":"Which of the following books has been written by Atiq Rahimi ?","Options":{"1":"Earth and Ashes","2":"This Savage Rite","3":"The Red Devil","4":"Witness the Night"},"Answer":"Earth and Ashes"},{"QuestionID":"GKSports00001","Question":"The 65th National Football Championship (Santosh Trophy 2011) was won by","Options":{"1":"Bangal","2":"Punjab","3":"Manipur","4":"Goa"},"Answer":"Bangal"},{"QuestionID":"GKImpSch00001","Question":"The Educational Development Index (EDI) Report, released in 2011, is led by","Options":{"1":"Tamil Nadu","2":"Puducherry","3":"Kerala","4":"Lakshadweep"},"Answer":"Kerala"},{"QuestionID":"GKImpDay00001","Question":"As per 2011 census, in India the number of females per thousands mails is","Options":{"1":"940","2":"934","3":"933","4":"972"},"Answer":"940"},{"QuestionID":"GKPplNws00001","Question":"Who is the recipient of the Sahitya Akademi Award 2010 in Hindi Literature category ?","Options":{"1":"Uday Prakash","2":"Laxman Dubey","3":"Nanjil Nandan","4":"Mangat Badal"},"Answer":"Uday Prakash"},{"QuestionID":"QANnmSys00001","Question":"Which of the following is divisible by 99 ?","Options":{"1":"114345","2":"3572404","3":"135792","4":"913464"},"Answer":"114345"},{"QuestionID":"QANnmSys00003","Question":"The sum of square of first 50 natural numbers is","Options":{"1":"40000","2":"58725","3":"42925","4":"255025"},"Answer":"42925"},{"QuestionID":"QAHCFLCM00002","Question":"Two numbers are in the ratio 3 : 4. There L.C.M is 84. The greater number is","Options":{"1":"21","2":"24","3":"28","4":"84"},"Answer":"28"},{"QuestionID":"QASimFic00002","Question":"<math display='inline'><mfrac><msup><mn>(256 x 256 − 144 x 144)</mn></msup><mn>112</mn></mfrac></math> is equal to","Options":{"1":"420","2":"400","3":"360","4":"320"},"Answer":"400"},{"QuestionID":"QASCRoot00002","Question":"<span>a<sup>3</sup> + <math display='inline'><mfrac><mn>1</mn><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>3</mn></msup></mfrac></math> = 2</span>, then the value of     <math display='block'><mrow><mfrac><mrow><mrow><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup></mrow><mo>+</mo><mrow><mn>1</mn></mrow></mrow><mrow><mn>a</mn></mrow></mfrac></mrow></math>is (a is positive number","Options":{"1":"1","2":"2","3":"2","4":"4"},"Answer":"2"},{"QuestionID":"QASCRoot00001","Question":"If a=2, b=−3 then the value of <span>27a<sup>3</sup> − 54a<sup>2</sup>b + 36ab<sup>2</sup> − 8b<sup>3</sup></span> is","Options":{"1":"1562","2":"1616","3":"1676","4":"1728"},"Answer":"1728"},{"QuestionID":"QARatPro00001","Question":"If 10% of x is 3 times 15% of y, then find x : y.","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"7 : 2","2":"9 : 2","3":"8 : 3","4":"77 : 4"},"Answer":"9 : 2"},{"QuestionID":"QAAvgSir00001","Question":"The average of runs of a cricket player if 20 innings was 32. How many runs must he make in his next innings so as to increase his average of runs by 4?","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"116","2":"114","3":"170","4":"76"},"Answer":"116"},{"QuestionID":"QAPerCal00001","Question":"If the price of sugar increase by 20%, one can buy 2 kg less for Rs.50. what is the amount of sugar that could be bought before price hike?","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"10 kg","2":"12 kg","3":"14 kg","4":"16 kg"},"Answer":"12 kg"},{"QuestionID":"QAPrfLos00001","Question":"A men gains 20% by selling an article for a certain price. If he sells it at double the price, the percentage of profit will be","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"40%","2":"100%","3":"120%","4":"140%"},"Answer":"140%"},{"QuestionID":"QAPrfLos00002","Question":"A men buys a watch for Rs.1950 in cash and sells it for Rs.2200 at a credit of 1 year. If the rat of interest be 10% per annum, then how much profit or loss will he have?","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"Rs. 55 gain","2":"Rs. 30 profit","3":"rs. 30 loss","4":"Rs. 55 loss"},"Answer":"Rs. 55 gain"},{"QuestionID":"QATimWrk00001","Question":"12 men and 16 boys can do a piece of work in 5 days; 13 men and 24 boys can do it in 4 days, then the ratio of the daily work done by a man to that of a boy is","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"2 : 1","2":"3 : 1","3":"1 : 3","4":"5 : 4"},"Answer":"2 : 1"},{"QuestionID":"QATimDis00001","Question":"A man can row upstream at 12 km/hr and downstream at 18 km/hr. The man's rowing speed in still water is","QuestionImg":null,"Options":{"1":"15 km/hr","2":"5 km/hr","3":"3 km/hr","4":"10 km/hr"},"Answer":"15 km/hr"},{"QuestionID":"ENGSynSi00007","Question":"Which of the word is most similar in meaning to the given word: RELISH","Options":{"1":"Desire","2":"Nibble","3":"Savour","4":"Avail"},"Answer":"Savour"},{"QuestionID":"ENGAntOp00001","Question":"Which of the word opposite in meaning to the word: FLORID","Options":{"1":"Weak","2":"Pale","3":"Monotonous","4":"Ugly"},"Answer":"Pale"},{"QuestionID":"ENGSpelT00001","Question":"Four words are given, out of which only one word is spelt correctly. Choose the correctly spelt word","Options":{"1":"Definite","2":"Diffinite","3":"Defenite","4":"Difinite"},"Answer":"Definite"},{"QuestionID":"ENSptErr00011","Question":"Find out which pare of a sentence has an error. The number of that part is your answer. Your answer is (4) i.e. No error","Options":{"1":"It is pity","2":"that even five years old boys","3":"are engaged in hazardous factories.","4":"No error"},"Answer":"that even five years old boys"},{"QuestionID":"ENSptErr00012","Question":"Find out which pare of a sentence has an error. The number of that part is your answer. Your answer is (4) i.e. No error","Options":{"1":"I gave him","2":"two hundred rupee notes","3":"for depositing","4":"No error"},"Answer":"two hundred rupee notes"},{"QuestionID":"ENSptErr00006","Question":"Find out which pare of a sentence has an error. The number of that part is your answer. Your answer is (4) i.e. No error","Options":{"1":"Children are prone","2":"to making mischiefs","3":"if they have nothing to do.","4":"No error"},"Answer":"to making mischiefs"},{"QuestionID":"ENOnWdSu00001","Question":"To examine one's own thought and feelings","Options":{"1":"Meditation","2":"Retrospection","3":"Reflection","4":"Introspection"},"Answer":"Introspection"},{"QuestionID":"ENOnWdSu00004","Question":"Anything written in a letter after it is signed","Options":{"1":"Posterity","2":"Post-diction","3":"Postscript","4":"Corrigendum"},"Answer":"Postscript"},{"QuestionID":"ENOnWdSu00008","Question":"To send an unwanted person out of the country","Options":{"1":"Exclude","2":"Ostracise","3":"Deport","4":"Expatriate"},"Answer":"Deport"},{"QuestionID":"ENGIdaPh00010","Question":"To meet one's waterloo","Options":{"1":"To meet a strong adversary","2":"To meet with humiliation","3":"To die fighting","4":"To meet one's final defeat"},"Answer":"To meet one's final defeat"},{"QuestionID":"ENGIdaPh00002","Question":"To wash dirty linen in public","Options":{"1":"To quarrel openly","2":"To clean solid lines","3":"To understand the hidden meaning of the world","4":"To wash dirty clothes"},"Answer":"To understand the hidden meaning of the world"},{"QuestionID":"ENGIdaPh00008","Question":"To flog a dead horse","Options":{"1":"To revive interest in a subject which is out of date","2":"To beat a horse that is dead","3":"To do interesting things","4":"To try to take work from a weak horse"},"Answer":"To revive interest in a subject which is out of date"}]}